Guide to the Wayne A. Meeks Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Wayne A. Meeks Papers
1959-2014
RG 269
Yale University Divinity School Library
8.5
(21 boxes)
Writings, correspondence, and course-related materials document the academic career of prominent New Testament scholar Wayne A. Meeks, who taught in the Religious Studies Department at Yale University from 1969 until his retirement in 1999.
Meeks, Wayne A.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence
II. Documentation of Professional Activities
III. HarperCollins Study Bible Project
IV. Courses Taught
V. Dissertations Advised
VI. Personal Items and Memorabilia
Biographical / Historical
Biographical Information
Chronology
1932 January 8 Born in Aliceville, Alabama
1953 Received B.S. degree from University of Alabama
1956 Received B.D. degree from Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary
1956-1957 Study at University of Tübingen as Fulbright scholar
1964, 1965 Received M.A., Ph.D. degrees from Yale University (Religious Studies: New Testament)
1964-1965 Instructor in Religion at Dartmouth College
1966-1969 Assistant / Associate Professor of Religious Studies at Indiana University
1969-1973 Associate Professor of Religious Studies at Yale University
1973- Professor of Religious Studies at Yale University
1984- Woolsey Professor of Religious Studies at Yale University
1999- Professor Emeritus of Religious Studies at Yale University
2004 Fall McDonald Visiting Distinguished Professor in the Study of the Person and Teachings of Jesus at Emory University
2005 Spring Croghan Bicentennial Visiting Professor in Biblical and Early Christian Studies at Williams College
Prof. Meeks served as Chairman of Department of Religious Studies at Yale from 1972 to 1975 and Acting Chairman 1978-1979 and 1982-1983. He was Director, Division of the Humanities, 1988-1991.
He was General Editor of the HarperCollins Study Bible (Society of Biblical Literature)from 1989-1993 and General Editor of the Library of Early Christianity, Westminster Press, 1982-1987. For additional professional activities see Meeks' Curriculum Vitae in Series VI.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Wayne A. Meeks, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the academic career of prominent Yale University faculty member and New Testament scholar Wayne Meeks. Meeks is best known for his publications on the writings of the apostle Paul and on the Fourth Gospel, for his investigation of the social history of earliest Christianity, and for work on the formation of early Christian morality.
Correspondence with colleagues and students contained in both Series I, Correspondence, and Series II, Documentation of Professional Activities, provides insight into issues of interest for the community of scholarship in the field of New Testament studies. Colleagues with whom Meeks corresponded include Elaine Pagels, Jacob Neusner, Ernest Frerichs, Victor Paul Furnish, Helmut Koester, David L. Balch, Troels Engberg-Pedersen,and many others.
Writings, talks, and lectures by Meeks are interspersed throughout Series II, many of them unpublished typescripts. When the title of a paper or lecture is listed, a text is generally available; in other cases the files may contain primarily information about a lecture or event. Meeks' Curriculum Vitae in Series VI provides a full listing of published articles, essays, and books.
Series III focuses on Meeks' work as General Editor of the HarperCollins Study Bible, a reference work that combines the text of the New Revised Standard Version of the Bible with notes by sixty leading Biblical scholars.
Series IV, Courses Taught, and Series V, Dissertations Advised, provide thorough documentation of Meeks' teaching and advisory activities, primarily at Yale.
Series VI, Personal Items and Memorabilia, contains primarily biographical information.
Biblical scholars; Meeks, Wayne A.; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Religious Studies; Meeks, Wayne A.
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Chronological sequence
    - With colleagues, with W.W. Norton Company Publishers, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1981 March - 1982 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1982 April - July (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1982 July - December (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1983 January - May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1983 June - December (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1984 January - June (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1984 July - December (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1985 January - April (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1985 May - October (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1985 November - December (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1986 January - March (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1986 April - May (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1986 June - December (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1987 January - May (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1987 June - September (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - With colleagues, students, and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1987 October - December (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1988 January - March (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1988 April - July (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1988 August - December (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1989 January - May (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1989 June - December (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1993 January - May (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1993 July - December (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - With colleagues and students and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - With colleagues and regarding positions, projects, publications, 1998-1999, no date (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - With students and potential students
    - Regarding admission, courses, recommendations, etc., 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Regarding admission, courses, recommendations, etc., 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Regarding admission, courses, recommendations, etc., 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Regarding admission, courses, recommendations, etc., 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Documentation of Professional Activities, Series II
  - Graduate school fellowships, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of The Prophet King: Moses Traditions and the Johannine Christology, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Comparative Midrash: An Emerging Subdiscipline", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Comments delivered by Meeks at the opening of a symposium on Comparative Midrash at the Annual Meeting of the American Academy of Religion, New York, October 24, 1970.
  - National Endowment for the Humanities fellowship, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of The Writings of St. Paul, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Regarding The Writings of Saint Paul, A Norton Critical Edition (W.W. Norton & Company Publishers), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Regarding The Writings of Saint Paul, A Norton Critical Edition (W.W. Norton & Company Publishers), 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Revised Standard Bible Committee: Correspondence with members, memorandum, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Regarding volume on Colossians, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Edited by Wayne Meeks and Fred Francis for the Society of Biblical Literature series "Sources and Documents"
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) Seminar: Johannine Christianity, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "The Schools of Two Great Pharisaic Escape Artists: Toward a Comparison of Pauline Christianity and the Innovations of Yavneh", 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Lecture given by Meeks at Amherst.
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) Seminar on Johannine Christianity in Scotland, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Montreat Lectures, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    "Using the Bible in Becoming the Church"; "Reciting and Celebrating: Studies in Liturgy and Festival"; "Remembering in Antioch: Studies in Ethical Formation"; "Participating in the Story: Studies in Narrative."
  - Aufstieg und Niedergang der romischen Welt Project, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Proposed essay by Meeks on "The Social World of Pauline Christianity"
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) Seminar in Johannine Christianity at Duke University, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NEH Summer Seminar on "The Social World of Early Christianity", 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Regarding Jews and Christians in Antioch: In the First Four Centuries of the Common Era by Wayne A. Meeks and Robert L. Wilken, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Social History and/or Sacred Text": symposium at Society of Biblical Literature regional meeting in Brighton, MA., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Studiorium Novi Testamenti Societas meeting in Paris, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "The Social World of Early Christianity" NEH summer seminar for college teachers, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Regarding volume on sociology and the New Testament, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Colloquium on Apocalyptic, University of Uppsala, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Regarding Zur Soziologie des Urchristentums, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Princeton University Department of Religion, Advisory Council Meeting, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Studying Religion at Bucknell University - An Evaluation of the Department of Religion", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut College Visiting Committee (1 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut College Visiting Committee (2 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Westminster Press series: The Library of Early Christianity (1 of 4), 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence with colleagues and publisher about the works of Wayne Meeks
  - Westminster Press series: The Library of Early Christianity (2 of 4), 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Westminster Press series: The Library of Early Christianity (3 of 4), 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Westminster Press series: The Library of Early Christianity (4 of 4), 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Correspondence and Notes regarding text.
  - Westminster Press series: re, Christology in Context volume by M. de Jonge (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Westminster Press series: re. Christology in Context volume by M. de Jonge (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Social Experience and Faith in the Churches of Paul" - Tate-Wilson Lectures, Southern Methodist University., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Series of three lectures including: "Striking Root, The City and the Ekklesia of God," "Shaping Memory and Life: Ritual in Pauline Christianity," "Believing as a Social Act."
  - Sermon, Battell Chapel, Yale University, on Jonah 3:1-5,10;1 Cor 7:29-31; Mark 1:14-20, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "The Role of Pauline Christianity in the Emergence of Rational, Ethical Religion", 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Lecture presented at Colloquium on Max Weber's Analysis of the History of the Ancient Mediterranean World, Werner-Reimers-Stiftung, Bad Homburg
  - "The Urban Communities of the Apostle Paul," talk presented at the Principia College, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Article not included
  - Hellenistic Seminar, Concordia College, Montreal, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Early Christians: What Did the Neighbors Think?" - Herbert G. May Memorial Lecture at Oberlin College, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "The Greek Encounter with Judaism in the Hellenistic Period," presented to Professor Louis Feldman's NEH Summer Seminar, Yeshiva College, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - SBL, AAR, Association for the Scientific Study of Religion, American Schools of Oriental Research - Southwest Region meetings Dallas, Texas, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Colloquium at Program in Judaic Studies, Brown University, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Haverford College Spring Symposium, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Judeans, Galileans, Samaritans, and the Johannine Christians" - presented at Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas 39th General Meeting, Basel, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Seminar Application, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Seminar at University of Iowa, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "From Sect to Rival: Reflections on Christianity's Separation from Judaism" - lecture presented at University of Pittsburgh, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    No text available
  - "Breaking Away: Three New Testament Pictures of Christianity's Separation from the Jewish Communities" - presented at "To See Ourselves as Others See Us" conference, Brown University, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "The Origin of Christianity: A New Look at an Old Puzzle" - Otts Lectures, Davidson College, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Christianity: From the Beginning to A.D. 235" - for Storia di Roma, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Troy Conference Pastor's School "Community and Conduct: the Formation of Moral Intuitions in Early Christianity, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Studying the Bible as Memory and Liberation," presented at "Conference on the Study of the Bible in the Liberal Arts" at Wabash College, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Dim Mirrors of the New Creation: Elements of Moral Discernment in the Early Church" - Rauschenbush Lectures, Colgate Rochester Divinity School, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Westervelt Lectures at The Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Circle of Reference in Pauline Morality," delivered at Texas Christian University, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "What Kind of Movement Were the Followers of Jesus?" - Frei Lecture, Ezra Stiles College, Yale University, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Keynote Speaker at United Church of Christ Consultation XII on Parish Ministry, Orlando, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Wickenden Lectures, Miami University, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hartford Seminary, Faculty Development Seminar, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "The Writings of St. Paul and His School," "Paul's Place in Early Christianity" - lecture for NCC RSV project, Standard Video Bible Study, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Regarding J. Louis Martyn Festscrift, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Theological Union, Cooperative Summer Session "The Moral World of the First Christians", 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Revisions for The Writings of St. Paul Second edition (1 of 2), 1989-2006 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Revisions for The Writings of St. Paul Second edition (2 of 2), 1989-2006 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Koester Festschrift, "The Future of Early Christianity", 1989 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Regarding Greeks, Romans, and Christians: Essays in Honor of Abraham J. Malherbe, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "The Puzzle of Christian Beginnings " - McMartin Lecture, Carleton University, Ottawa, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lectures at St. Olaf College Theology and Music Conference, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Lecture 1 "Making Morals Means Making Community," Lecture 2 "Moral Discourse: A New Symphony, " Lecture 3, "The Moral of the Story/ The Story of the Moral,"
  - "On Trusting an Unpredictable God: A Hermeneutical Meditation on Romans 9-11" - lecture at University of Uppsala, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Outline of presentation "Is An Ethnography of Early Thessalonian Christianity Possible?" - for Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS), Milan, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "'To Walk Worthily of the Lord': Moral Formation in the Pauline School Exemplified by the Letter to Colossians", 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Presented at - Conference on Philosophical Theology and Biblical Exegesis, Notre Dame University
  - Conference on Philosophical Theology and Biblical Exegesis, Notre Dame University, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Colwell Lecture at Claremont School of Theology, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "On Trusting an Unpredictable God: A Hermeneutical Meditation on Romans 9-11" for Faith and History: Essays in Honor of Paul W. Meyer, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Regarding Oxford Study Bible, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Meetings and correspondence with Oxford University Press
  - Speaker's Lecturer in Biblical Studies, Oxford University, 1989/1990, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Asking Back to Jesus' Identity" - presented at M. De Jonge Colloquium, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "On Trusting an Unpredictable God: A Hermeneutical Meditation on Romans 9-11" - presented at University of Cambridge, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - External reviewer for University of Notre Dame, Department of Theology, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Paul and the Transformation of Status A Reading of Philemon" - presented at Graduate Institute on Contemporary Christian Thought at St. Joseph College, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Presentations at Christ Church Cathedral Lenten Brunch Program, Hartford CT, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "The Puzzle of Christian Beginnings" - presented at Celebrating Moral Thought, Sunstone Symposium XIII in Salt Lake City, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Naming of Jesus in Early Christianity: History, Midrash, and Myth" - presented at McMaster University, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Report on Site Visit to the Department of Religion, Duke University, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Community and Moral Formation in Early Christianity" seminar in South Africa, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "In The Footsteps of St. Paul: Retracing St. Paul's Voyages from Israel to Cyprus, Turkey & Greece" - study tour arranged by the Smithsonian National Associate Program (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "In The Footsteps of St. Paul: Retracing St. Paul's Voyages from Israel to Cyprus, Turkey & Greece" - study tour arranged by the Smithsonian National Associate Program (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Regarding Festscrift for Lars Hartman, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "The Mystery of History: A Response To Hans Dieter Betz" - presented at the SBL Annual Meeting, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - External Consultant for the review of Religious Studies at McMaster University, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "The Enigma of Paul," foreword for "St. Paul" by Arthur D. Nock (The Easton Press), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lecture at Washington Theological Union, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "The Sacred Body in Law and Literature" conference at Yale University, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Fishmongers, Silversmiths ... of Tyrannos: Christians and Clubs at Ephesus" - presented at Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS), Scotland, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Judaism, Hellenism, and the Birth of Christianity" - Danforth Lecture, Hope College, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Jews, Judaisms, and the Birth of Christianity" Haskell Lectures, Oberlin College, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "History, Pluralism, and Christian Morality" - 7th Annual Michael Boone McGowen Memorial Series, John Knox Presbyterian Church of Tulsa, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "How My Mind Has Changed," presented at the Society of Biblical Literature Annual Meeting, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Regarding Festschrift for D. Moody Smith, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "A Response to 'Koinonia in Scripture' by John Reumann" - World Council of Churches, Faith and Order Conference, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "On Not Giving An Inch: A Response to Meeks' Account of Why History Matters for Ethics," by Stanley Hauerwas, in The Journal of Religious Ethics, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Luke's Project: Eyewitness and Servants of the Word (or: a Historian Tries to Bear Witness)" - presented at Loyola College of Maryland, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Sheffield Dinner at Society of Biblical Literature, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Regarding Cambridge Companion to Biblical Interpretation, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "The New Testament and Ethics: Problems and Prospectus" - symposium at Duke University, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Regarding Festschrift for Victor Paul Furnish (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "Judaism, Hellenism, and the Birth of Christianity," presented at Saint Stephen's Episcopal Church, Aliceville, Alabama, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Talk on Romans to Literature Humanities faculty at Columbia College, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "The Origins of Christianity: From Jewish Sect to Imperial Religion" - Patricia Prescott May Academic Lectures, The Field Club of Greenwich, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Institute on Sacred Scripture, College Misericordia, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Association of Yale Alumni, Journey Into Ancient Lands: Syria, Jordan, and Israel, Travel Seminar, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Society of Biblical Studies meeting, Newfoundland, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "The Quest" A four-hour historical documentary television series to be produced by WGBH/Boston for the Public Broadcasting Service, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Association of Yale Alumni trip: Greece and Rome: Cradles of Civilization, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Vision of God and Scripture Interpretation in a Fifth-century Mosaic" by Wayne A. and Martha F. Meeks presented at St. John's School of Theology, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Judaism, Hellenism, and the Birth of Christianity" - presented at the Institute for Biblical and Literary Studies, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Halstead Lecture at Drew University, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Corinthian Christians as Artificial Aliens," and "Judaism, Hellenism, and the Birth of Christianity", 1997 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Presented at "Paul Between Judaism and Hellenism, The Corinthian Correspondence in Context" conference in Copenhagen
  - "Christian Beginnings and Christian Ethics: The Hermeneutical Challenge" - presented at the European Society of Catholic Theologians, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "The Strange Case of Gerhard Kittel" - presented at Society of Biblical Literature, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Lessons from the First Urban Christians?" - presented at St. James Church, NYC, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Apocalypse Now" - presented atThe Foundation for Biblical Research, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Christians in the City" and "Reflection on 'The Moral World of the First Christians' and 'The Origins of Christian Morality'" - presented at Emory University, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 13)